<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>juko on Tejas Siripurapu</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/tags/juko/</link><description>Recent content in juko on Tejas Siripurapu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Athul</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tejas.wtf/tags/juko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Juko V2</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/posts/juko-v2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tejas.wtf/posts/juko-v2/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction to Juko Juko V1: The Original Idea Juko Reimagined: Interactive Music Discovery Sessions\n a. Design: User Story + Figma\n b. Building: Django, React, Docker, GHA\n c. Deploying: GKE, Kubernetes, Kustomize\n Conclusion Appendix Introduction to Juko Juko started out as a &amp;ldquo;startup idea&amp;rdquo; after I graduated from college (Dec 2019) and was struggling to find work at the start of the pandemic (a.k.a. the pando). I use the quotes because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I ever seriously believed this idea had the legs to become anything substantial.</description></item><item><title>Defining Music Services: Artist-facing vs. Listener-facing</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/posts/defining-music-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tejas.wtf/posts/defining-music-services/</guid><description>Introduction When people think of music services they often think of streaming services like Spotify, Apple Music, and the like. While these are the largest players in the music services industry, streaming is far from the only service provided in the music industry. Music services can largely be split into two categories: listener-facing and artist-facing services. Listener-facing services are those which are geared towards helping listeners find new music (music discovery), save and store music they like, and listen to music by streaming remotely (Spotify) or playing from local storage (iTunes).</description></item><item><title>Problems in the Music Industry: The Need for Better Recommenders and Improved Music Discovery</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/posts/music-discovery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tejas.wtf/posts/music-discovery/</guid><description>Introduction Since artist compensation is dependent on the number of streams an artist can generate and the barrier of entry into music, in terms of distribution, is much lower, the entire pool of music available for streaming has become oversaturated with subpar songs and, more generally, the amount of readily streamable music is increasing rapidly. Building improved music discovery services and recommendation systems would solve these issues.
Artist Compensation and Counting Streams Firstly, the current model for compensating artists (adopted by Spotify and Apple Music, the two largest music streaming service providers) is entirely dependent on the number of streams an artist can generate.</description></item></channel></rss>