<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music discovery on Tejas Siripurapu</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/tags/music-discovery/</link><description>Recent content in music discovery on Tejas Siripurapu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Athul</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tejas.wtf/tags/music-discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Problems in the Music Industry: The Need for Better Recommenders and Improved Music Discovery</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/posts/music-discovery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tejas.wtf/posts/music-discovery/</guid><description>Introduction: Since artist compensation is dependent on the number of streams an artist can generate and the barrier of entry into music, in terms of distribution, is much lower, the entire pool of music available for streaming has become oversaturated with subpar songs and, more generally, the amount of readily streamable music is increasing rapidly. Building improved music discovery services and recommendation systems would solve these issues.
Artist Compensation and Counting Streams Firstly, the current model for compensating artists (adopted by Spotify and Apple Music, the two largest music streaming service providers) is entirely dependent on the number of streams an artist can generate.</description></item><item><title>Recommendations Based on Pitchfork Written Reviews</title><link>https://tejas.wtf/notebooks/pitchfork_review_rec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tejas.wtf/notebooks/pitchfork_review_rec/</guid><description>Introduction Setup First, let&amp;rsquo;s make sure we&amp;rsquo;re in the correct working directory and have all the necessary packages imported. We&amp;rsquo;ll also read in the dataset&amp;ndash;It&amp;rsquo;s been cleaned beforehand on my local machine; a simple process to get it into a csv rather than the SQLLite db I had downloaded. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ll set a flag to indicate which vectorizer we are using in the interest of testing both and comparing (A/B testing).</description></item></channel></rss>